It's time for a new puzzle of the month.
This one starts with three pegs sitting in three corners of a square on the plane.
And we're going to play a game where at any time you can jump one peg over another one,
placing it an equal distance away on the other side.
So for example, you could have two pegs walk down a line kind of hopping
over one another like this as far as they want to their heart's content.
But you don't have to go in a straight line, you can also go diagonally.
This peg could jump over this one, for example,
or maybe this one could jump over this one, giving you an even different
angle of movement.
The question is, given our initial configuration of three pegs on three
corners of a square, can you get a peg to this fourth corner of the square?
If the answer is yes, find with a proof the smallest
number of moves required to get there.
If you think the answer is no, you would have to prove that it's impossible.